<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Scorpiosec</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Scorpiosec</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:38:38 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scorpiosec.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HTB: Administrator</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-administrator/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Apr 2025 00:38:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-administrator/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Administrator Level: Medium OS: Windows This box is an assumed breach scenario, we are given credentials for the following account: Username: Olivia Password: ichliebedich
For the Administrator box, we begin by leveraging the provided credentials to run BloodHound, which reveals an attack path involving the GenericAll and ForceChangePassword permissions. By exploiting these, we compromise additional user accounts and access an FTP server containing a Password Safe (psafe3) database file.</description></item><item><title>HTB: LinkVortex</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-linkvortex/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 22:37:01 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-linkvortex/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: LinkVortex Level: Easy OS: Linux LinkVortex runs a vulnerable version of Ghost CMS. Through directory brute-forcing and subdomain enumeration, we discover the admin login page and an exposed .git directory, which contains valid credentials for authentication. We then leverage CVE-2023-40028, a file read vulnerability, to read sensitive files on the server, eventually finding another set of credentials. These allow us to gain an initial foothold via SSH.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Alert</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-alert/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 23:31:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-alert/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Alert Level: Easy OS: Linux The exploitation of Alert begins with the discovery of two XSS vulnerabilities, one of which exposes a Local File Inclusion (LFI) flaw. Leveraging this, we extract the contents of the .htpasswd file, revealing a hashed user password. After cracking the hash, we obtain valid credentials and gain an initial foothold on the target. Further system enumeration reveals an internally hosted website.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Chemistry</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-chemistry/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 19:59:10 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-chemistry/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Chemistry Level: Easy OS: Linux Chemistry starts with a file analyzer processing CIF files. Exploiting CVE-2024-23346, we gain an initial foothold by uploading a malicious CIF file. On the target, we discover a database file containing a password hash, enabling us to pivot to another user. Further enumeration reveals an internal website, which we access via tunneling. The website is vulnerable to CVE-2024-23334, allowing us to retrieve the root SSH key and complete the exploitation.</description></item><item><title>HTB Challenge: ApacheBlaze</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-apaxheblaze/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 21:11:49 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-apaxheblaze/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: ApacheBlaze Level: Easy Category: Web CHALLENGE DESCRIPTION Step into the ApacheBlaze universe, a world of arcade clicky games. Rumor has it that by playing certain games, you have the chance to win a grand prize. However, before you can dive into the fun, you&amp;rsquo;ll need to crack a puzzle.
ZIP PASSWORD: hackthebox
Website Enumeration At the target IP address we find a website with four different games to play.</description></item><item><title>THM: Rabbit Store</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-rabbit_store/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 21:16:11 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-rabbit_store/</guid><description>Platform: TryHackMe Link: Rabbit Store Level: Medium OS: Linux Rabbit Store presents a couple of uncommon services. The challenge begins with identifying a mass assignment vulnerability in an API, which is then leveraged alongside an SSRF vulnerability to retrieve the API documentation. One of the discovered endpoints is vulnerable to SSTI, allowing us to gain initial access to the target system. Through enumeration, we uncover an Erlang cookie, enabling us to pivot to another user.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Yummy</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-yummy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 02:00:16 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-yummy/</guid><description>Platform: HackTheBox Link: Yummy Level: Hard OS: Linux Yummy presents a relatively small attack surface. A Local File Inclusion (LFI) vulnerability, allows access to the application&amp;rsquo;s source code. The review of the code reveals weak RSA key generation for JWT authentication, enabling the creation of higher-privilege tokens.
Further enumeration of the admin dashboard leads to the discovery of an SQL injection vulnerability in the search function. Combined with the FILE privilege, this allows us to write some content into files on the system, leading to remote code execution.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Cicada</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-cicada/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 17:24:03 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-cicada/</guid><description>Platform: HackTheBox Link: Cicada Level: Easy OS: Windows Cicada is an Active Directory domain controller. We are able to login through SMB using the guest account, allowing us to retrieve a note containing a password. By performing a RID brute force attack, we enumerate the domain users and discover valid credentials, which we use to authenticate via LDAP. Further enumeration reveals a password stored in a user’s description field, granting access to another SMB share containing a PowerShell script with hardcoded credentials.</description></item><item><title>THM: You Got Mail</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-you-got-mail/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 14:59:41 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-you-got-mail/</guid><description>Platform: TryHackMe Link: You Got Mail Level: Medium OS: Windows This room focuses on a phishing attack. After collecting an email list, we use cewl to create a customized password list. Hydra, successfully recovers the password for one of the email accounts. With swaks, we send a phishing email that results in a reverse shell on the target system. From there, we retrieve the password for a user account as well as the admin password for hMailServer.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Trickster</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-trickster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:34 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-trickster/</guid><description>Platform: HackTheBox Link: Trickster Level: Medium OS: Linux Trickster is a multi-step machine beginning with the discovery of a subdomain containing a hidden .git directory, running an exploitable version of PrestaShop. Gaining initial access (with CVE-2024-34716) leads to the retrieval of database credentials from a configuration file, which help us find a user password.
System enumeration reveals an internal Docker interface with a host running a vulnerable instance of changedetection.</description></item><item><title>THM: Smol</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-smol/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 11:31:43 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-smol/</guid><description>Platform: TryHackMe Link: Smol Level: Medium OS: Linux Smol focuses on exploiting vulnerabilities in WordPress plugins. The challenge begins with enumerating a WordPress site using WPScan, where we discover a plugin vulnerable to Local File Inclusion (LFI). This allows us to extract credentials and log into the WordPress dashboard. Within the dashboard, a private note directs us to the source code of the Hello Dolly plugin, which contains a backdoor.</description></item><item><title>HTB: MonitorsThree</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-monitorsthree/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 10:06:34 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-monitorsthree/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: MonitorsThree Level: Medium OS: Linux MonitorsThree begins with a website on port 80 and a Cacti instance hosted on a subdomain. The Forgot Password? feature on the main site is vulnerable to SQL injection, which we exploit to retrieve the admin user&amp;rsquo;s password. Using these credentials, we access the Cacti dashboard and leverage CVE-2024-25641 to gain an initial foothold on the system. Further exploration reveals additional password hashes, enabling us to pivot to another user via SSH.</description></item><item><title>THM: Silver Platter</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-silverplatter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 21:00:11 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-silverplatter/</guid><description>Platform: TryHackMe Link: Silver Platter Level: Easy OS: Linux Silver Platter is a straightforward machine that begins with http services running on two different ports, one of which reveals a potential username. Through enumeration, we discover a Silverpeas login page and use a custom password list to identify valid credentials, granting access to the dashboard. Further research helps us find CVE-2023-47323, which we use to obtain another set of credentials and an initial foothold.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Compiled</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-compiled/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 13:44:19 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-compiled/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Compiled Level: Medium OS: Windows Compiled begins with the discovery of a Gitea instance running on port 3000 and a compilation service on port 5000. By exploiting a vulnerability in the identified Git version (CVE-2024-32002), we gain initial access. We explore the system and uncover a database file containing user hashes and other critical information, allowing us to crack a password and perform a lateral movement.</description></item><item><title>THM: Airplane</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-airplane/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 17:41:30 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-airplane/</guid><description>Platform: TryHackMe Link: Airplane Level: Medium OS: Linux The challenge Airplane begins by uncovering a Local File Inclusion (LFI) vulnerability. By exploiting it, we enumerate the target’s running processes and identify one linked to GdbServer. Using an ELF binary crafted with msfvenom, we exploit this tool to gain an initial foothold on the system. Further enumeration reveals a binary with the SUID bit set, enabling us to pivot to another user and retrieve the user flag.</description></item><item><title>THM: The Sticker Shop</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-thestickershop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 16:26:19 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-thestickershop/</guid><description>Platform: TryHackMe Link: The Sticker Shop Level: Easy This is a pretty straightforward room where we need to leverage a Cross-Site Scripting vulnerability in order to read the flag.
Scanning ./nmap_scan.sh &amp;lt;IP_PROVIDED&amp;gt; The_Sticker_Shop You can find the script I use to scan targets here.
Results
Running detailed scan on open ports: 22,8080 Starting Nmap 7.94SVN ( https://nmap.org ) at 2024-12-04 16:38 CST Nmap scan report for 10.10.139.96 Host is up (0.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Resource</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-resource/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 18:48:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-resource/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Resource Level: Hard OS: Linux Resource revolves around exploiting SSH and Certificate Authority files. The initial access is gained through a PHAR deserialization attack targeting a file upload feature. Next, we recover user credentials from a HAR file, which facilitates lateral movement to another user account. During this process, we discover certificate authority keys, enabling us to generate SSH keys and log in as yet another user.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Axlle</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-axlle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 17:00:51 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-axlle/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Axlle Level: Hard OS: Windows Axlle is a domain controller hosting a web server and an email server alongside standard Active Directory services. After conducting reconnaissance, we launch a phishing attack using a .xll attachment to gain an initial foothold. On the compromised target, we discover an .eml file containing details about an automated task. By leveraging this information, we craft a malicious .url file, enabling lateral movement to another user account and accessing the user flag.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Blazorized</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-blazorized/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 18:46:04 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-blazorized/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Blazorized Level: Hard OS: Windows Blazorized features a variety of Active Directory attacks. We begin by examining a web server hosting a Blazor WebAssembly application with restricted content access. Through enumeration, we locate several DLL files associated with the application. Decompiling one of these files reveals sensitive information, which we leverage to forge a JSON Web Token (JWT). This grants us access to an admin panel where we identify a SQL injection vulnerability, providing our initial foothold.</description></item><item><title>THM: SeeTwo</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-seetwo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 12:11:25 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-seetwo/</guid><description>Platform: TryHackMe Link: SeeTwo Level: Medium In this room we have to investigate a pcap file. At first we find what looks like some benign traffic, however after digging deeper we find an ELF binary containing some .pyc files. Decompiling one the file allows us to understand the tactics used by the attacker, and with a python script we find all the information we need.
Investigation Right after loading the pcap file, we get an overview of the traffic.</description></item><item><title>THM: Rabbit Hole</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-rabbithole/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 19:25:05 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-rabbithole/</guid><description>Platform: TryHackMe Link: Rabbit Hole Level: Hard OS: Linux Rabbit Hole is all about exploiting SQL injection. We discover a second-order SQL injection vulnerability after some failed Cross-Site scripting (XSS) attempts. Using this, we retrieve some password hashes, but they don’t lead to initial access. By combining a python script and a payload leveraging the PROCESSLIST command we successfully extract the query containing the admin user password which we use to login via SSH and read the flag.</description></item><item><title>THM: K2</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-k2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2024 14:16:05 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-k2/</guid><description>Platform: TryHackMe Link: K2 Level: Hard OS: Linux and Windows (The room has three different machines) Base Camp The Base Camp machine in the K2 challenge starts with a basic website. Initial enumeration reveals two subdomains linked to a ticketing system, one of which is vulnerable to Cross-Site Scripting (XSS). Using XSS, we steal a session cookie to access the admin dashboard, which is also susceptible to SQL injection. This flaw allows us to retrieve admin credentials, granting initial access.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Editorial</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-editorial/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 21:00:55 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-editorial/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Editorial Level: Easy OS: Linux Editorial is an easy Linux machine with a few interesting challenges. The web application is vulnerable to Server-Side Request Forgery (SSRF), but it requires fuzzing internal ports to uncover sensitive data. By exploiting an API endpoint, we retrieve credentials that grant initial access to the system. During further enumeration, we discover a series of Git commits, one of which exposes credentials for another user, enabling lateral movement.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Blurry</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-blurry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 19:31:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-blurry/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Blurry Level: Medium OS: Linux The Blurry machine demonstrates how Python modules and specific Python features can be exploited to compromise systems. The challenge begins with access to a ClearML instance, containing various experiments tied to a project. Using CVE-2024-24590, we gain our initial foothold by uploading a malicious artifact through the API, allowing us to retrieve the user flag. This write-up will detail two distinct methods for privilege escalation, showcasing different approaches to fully compromise the system.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Freelancer</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-freelancer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 13:36:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-freelancer/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Freelancer Level: Hard OS: Windows Freelancer begins with a website that allows the creation of various types of accounts. After registering, we exploit an Insecure Direct Object Reference (IDOR) vulnerability to gain access to an admin account. On the admin page, we find a SQL terminal, which we leverage to obtain an initial foothold.
Further exploration of the system reveals passwords in a configuration file, which we run against a user list, enabling us to pivot to another account and obtain the user flag.</description></item><item><title>HTB: BoardLight</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-boardlight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 22:53:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-boardlight/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: BoardLight Level: Easy OS: Linux BoardLight begins with a subdomain discovery where we find a Dolibarr instance, which we access by using default credentials. The initial foothold is obtained via a PHP reverse shell coupled with an uppercase manipulation technique. From there we discover a configuration file containing credentials, allowing us to take over another account. Finally, we gain root privileges by exploiting a vulnerability in Enlightenment.</description></item><item><title>HTB: SolarLab</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-solarlab/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 13:33:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-solarlab/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: SolarLab Level: Medium OS: Windows SolarLab begins with a basic website that, after enumeration, offers no direct exploitation paths. Shifting focus to SMB, we discover a document in a file share containing credentials. These credentials grant access to ReportHub, accessible at a subdomain found during previous enumeration. Upon examining its functionality, we identify that it generates PDFs using the vulnerable ReportLab library (CVE-2023-33733), which allows us to exploit this and gain initial access, recovering the user flag.</description></item><item><title>THM: Friday Overtime</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-fridayovertime/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 21:09:28 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-fridayovertime/</guid><description>Platform: TryHackMe Link: Friday Overtime Level: Medium For this blue team challenge we need to conduct an investigation and provide answers to some questions.
After launching the provided VM we login with the credentials ericatracy:Intel321!.
Who shared the malware samples? Right after logging in we find a document titled Urgent: Malicious Malware Artefacts Detected.
The author of the document is Oliver Bennett.
Answer: Oliver Bennett
What is the SHA1 hash of the file &amp;ldquo;pRsm.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Mailing</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-mailing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 23:42:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-mailing/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Mailing Level: Easy OS: Windows Mailing from HackTheBox is an interesting box. After our initial scan, we discover several email-related services. By exploiting an LFI vulnerability, we find two password hashes, and successfully cracking one of them gives us the admin password. We then use the recent MonikerLink vulnerability to retrieve a user&amp;rsquo;s NTLM hash, which provides us with our initial foothold. Privilege escalation is achieved by placing a malicious file in a specific directory where all files with the .</description></item><item><title>THM: Summit</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-summit/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 21:44:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-summit/</guid><description>This is a blue team challenge where we need to create defensive countermeasures for various malware samples. This will be achieved by using file hashes, IP addresses, firewall rules, DNS and sigma rules.
Platform: TryHackMe Link: Summit Level: Easy What is the first flag you receive after successfully detecting sample1.exe? After navigating to the link provided, go to Malware Snadbox, the file sample1.exe is already loaded and click on Submit for Analysis.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Runner</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-runner/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 19:24:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-runner/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Runner Level: Medium OS: Linux Runner starts with a basic website offering CI/CD solutions. Through subdomain enumeration, we uncover a vulnerable TeamCity instance (CVE-2023-42793), granting us access. A backup archive downloaded from this instance reveals a private SSH key and password hashes. Using the SSH key, we gain an initial foothold and retrieve the user flag. Further exploration uncovers another subdomain hosting a Portainer.io instance, which we access using the previously recovered credentials.</description></item><item><title>HTB: IClean</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-iclean/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 17:57:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-iclean/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: IClean Level: Medium OS: Linux IClean begins with a cleaning service website where we identify a form vulnerable to Cross-Site Scripting (XSS). Exploiting this vulnerability, we retrieve a session cookie and access the application dashboard. There, we discover an invoice generator susceptible to Server-Side Template Injection (SSTI), which provides our initial foothold. Further exploration reveals the database credentials, allowing us to recover password hashes. By cracking one of these hashes, we gain SSH access and retrieve the user flag.</description></item><item><title>HTB: WifineticTwo</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-wifinetictwo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 15:04:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-wifinetictwo/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: WifineticTwo Level: Medium OS: Linux WifineticTwo is a unique box focused on WiFi exploitation. The challenge begins with an accessible OpenPLC page using default credentials. Utilizing CVE-2021-31630, we gain an initial foothold and capture the user flag. Once inside the target system, we brute-force the WPS key, configure the wireless interface, and scan the default gateway to discover internal services. We then access the Lua Configuration Interface, set up a new password, log in via SSH, and retrieve the root flag.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Headless</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-headless/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 22:17:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-headless/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Headless Level: Easy OS: Linux Headless starts with a static website. Through enumeration, we identify a contact form vulnerable to Cross-Site Scripting (XSS), though basic payloads prove ineffective. By capturing the admin&amp;rsquo;s cookie value, we gain access to the dashboard page and establish our foothold through command injection. For privilege escalation, we exploit a custom script to take control of the root account.
Target IP address - 10.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Perfection</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-perfection/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 14:05:10 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-perfection/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Perfection Level: Easy OS: Linux Perfection begins with a straightforward website. Through enumeration, we identify a vulnerability to Server-Side Template Injection (SSTI), which we exploit to gain an initial foothold. We then discover a database file containing password hashes, but our initial attempts to crack them are unsuccessful. After reading the user&amp;rsquo;s emails, we learn that the passwords follow a specific format. Using this information, we employ a mask attack with Hashcat and successfully recover the password.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Office</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-office/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 23:28:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-office/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Office Level: Hard OS: Windows The Office box is a Windows Server 2022 running as a domain controller. The website hosted on the web server uses an outdated version of Joomla, which is vulnerable to CVE-2023-23752. By exploiting this vulnerability, we leak the MySQL database password. After some enumeration, we find a valid username for the password, granting us access to a shared folder containing a pcap file.</description></item><item><title>THM: CyberLens</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-cyberlens/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 14:37:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-cyberlens/</guid><description>CyberLens features a website with a metadata extraction feature. After some enumeration we discover that the feature is powered by Apache Tika, an outadated version of the software vulnerable to CVE-2018-1335 is running. We get our initial foothold by exploiting the vulnerability. For privilege escalation we abuse AlwaysInstallElevated to obtain a system shell.
Scanning We will use a Bash script to automate the scanning process. You can find it here.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Crafty</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-crafty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 21:19:39 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-crafty/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Crafty Level: Easy OS: Windows Crafty is a Windows Server 2019 running Minecraft 1.16.5, this version is vulnerable to Log4Shell (CVE-2021-44228) and after using a PoC of the exploit we gain our initial foothold. On the target system, we find an archive containing some credential that we use to obtain an administrative shell.
Target IP - 10.10.11.249
Scanning sudo nmap -sC -sV -p- -oA nmap/Crafty 10.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Pov</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-pov/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 12:42:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-pov/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Pov Level: Medium OS: Windows Pov starts with a basic static website. After some enumeration, we discover a subdomain leading to an ASP.NET website that turns out to be vulnerable to LFI. Leveraging this vulnerability, we are able to read a critical file exposing sensitive information that we use to exploit the ViewState mechanism of the website, granting us our initial foothold. After exploring the target system, we move laterally to another user after finding and revealing their credentials.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Bizness</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-bizness/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 21:18:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-bizness/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Bizness Level: Easy OS: Linux Bizness is showcasing a web application powered by Apache OFBiz. During our investigation of vulnerabilities in the software, we identify one that allows attackers to bypass authentication. Leveraging this exploit, we gain our initial foothold. Next, we stumble upon a directory for Apache Derby that containing numerous .dat files. Our task is to sift through these files. Using some command-line magic, we manage to retrieve a password hash.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Monitored</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-monitored/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 21:41:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-monitored/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Monitored Level: Medium OS: Linux Monitored emphasizes rigorous enumeration, the challenge starts with a login form for Nagios XI and directory enumeration leads to the discovery of more and more endpoints. After exhausting all the leads from our nmap TCP scan we make use of a UDP scan to find an exploitable service leading to the leakage of credentials that we use to login. We are able to discover the software version on the target and we leverage CVE-2023-40931 to add a new admin account to the Nagios XI instance to grant us access.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Surveillance</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-surveillance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 15:48:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-surveillance/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Surveillance Level: Medium OS: Linux Surveillance begins with the discovery of a web application running on port 80, after identifying the software version, we use CVE-2023-41892 to gain initial access. Through further exploration, we find a database backup leaking the user name and password hash for an admin user, which we utilize to SSH into the system and uncover an internal service. Leveraging SSH tunneling, we access the service and make use of CVE-2023-26035 to exploit it.</description></item><item><title>THM: Creative</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-creative/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 22:14:41 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-creative/</guid><description>Platform: TryHackMe Link: Creative Level: Easy OS: Linux The challenge begins with a static website that is unexploitable. Through subdomain enumeration, a URL testing application is uncovered, susceptible to SSRF. However, full exploitation is only possible after discovering an internally exposed port. This access allows for file reading on the server, leading to the retrieval of an SSH private key. Yet, this alone isn&amp;rsquo;t enough to establish a foothold. Success is achieved by cracking the obtained SSH key&amp;rsquo;s hash, granting access to the target system.</description></item><item><title>THM: Clocky</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-clocky/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 13:03:18 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-clocky/</guid><description>Platform: TryHackMe Link: Clocky Level: Medium OS: Linux For this challenge our objective is to locate six flags. Our inital step involves examining the robots.txt file which contains some file extensions. By fuzzing with those file extensions we obtain an archive and extracting it yields the source code of an application. Upon reviewing the code we identify a way to manipulate the application&amp;rsquo;s password reset mechanism, granting us access to the administrative dashboard.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Codify</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-codify/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 16:50:10 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-codify/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Codify Level: Easy OS: Linux Codify starts with a web application that offers a sandbox environment for testing Node.js code. It utilizes the vm2 library and employs a module whitelist for security. However, there is a vulnerability (CVE-2023-3214 ) in vm2 that can be exploited to break out of the sandbox and access the target system. This is followed by lateral movement to access another user account and obtain the user flag.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Analytics</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-analytics/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 01:25:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-analytics/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Analytics Level: Easy OS: Linux Analytics features a Metabase instance, which is an open-source business intelligence software. The target is vulnerable to CVE-2023-38646 allowing command execution while unauthenticated. After enumerating the environment varialbles, SSH credentials are discovered and the root shell is gained via a kernel exploit.
Target IP Address - 10.10.11.233
Scanning nmap -sC -sV -oA nmap/Analytics 10.10.11.233 Results
Starting Nmap 7.94SVN ( https://nmap.</description></item><item><title>THM: Hack Smarter Security</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-hacksmartersecurity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2024 16:28:33 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-hacksmartersecurity/</guid><description>Platform: TryHackMe Link: Hack Smarter Security Level: Medium OS: Windows In this challenge we exploit a Windows Server machine feature SSH (which is not usual). After exploiting an uncommon service we find ourselves having to bypass Windows Defender in order to achieve administrative privileges.
The target IP address is 10.10.189.226.
Recon nmap -sC -sV -oA nmap/Hack-Smarter-Security 10.10.189.226 Several ports are found to be opened:
FTP is running on port 21, with anonymous login allowed SSH on port 22, which can potentially be our way into the system if credentials are found A Windows IIS server is running on port 80 From the nmap results it is not clear which service is running on port 1311 Windows WBT server is running on port 3389, this is used for Windows Remote Desktop and Remote Assistance connections Starting Nmap 7.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Manager</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-manager/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2024 22:14:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-manager/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Manager Level: Medium OS: Windows Manager is featuring a Windows server 2019 running Active Directory and a MSSQL database in addtion to various other services. The target is vulnerable to RID brute forcing and ESC7 (Vulnerable Certificate Authority Access Control).
The target IP address is 10.10.11.236
Scanning I first check all the open ports.
nmap 10.10.11.236 -p- -T4 -Pn --open Starting Nmap 7.94SVN ( https://nmap.</description></item><item><title>HTB: CozyHosting</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-cozyhosting/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 11:10:54 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-cozyhosting/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: CozyHosting Level: Easy OS: Linux CozyHosting is an easy Linux machine featuring a Hosting website vulnerable to command injection and the root is accessed by abusing the SSH binary.
The target IP address is 10.10.11.230
Scanning sudo nmap -sC -sV -oA nmap/CozyHosting 10.10.11.230 We have a Linux machine Running a web application on port 80 The SSH service is enabled on the target Starting Nmap 7.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Visual</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-visual/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2024 19:37:32 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-visual/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Visual Level: Medium OS: Windows Target IP address is 10.10.11.234
Scanning sudo nmap -sC -sV -oA nmap/Visual 10.10.11.234 I run my usual scan and I get some information:
Apache web server is running on the target It is a Windows machine (Though you can see that on the machine page) A PHP application is hosted on the machine running on port 80 Starting Nmap 7.</description></item><item><title>THM: OhSINT</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-ohsint/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 14:31:59 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-ohsint/</guid><description>Platform: TryHackMe Link: OhSINT Level: Easy Type: OSINT This is an OSINT challenge, OSINT stands for Open-Source Intelligence. It&amp;rsquo;s essentially the collection and analysis of publicly available information to gain valuable insights. Think of it like putting together a puzzle using pieces you find scattered around the internet, libraries, or anywhere information is freely accessible.
After downloading the Task Files, with the Download Task Files button you get a single image named WindowsXP.</description></item></channel></rss>