<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scorpiosec</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/</link><description>Recent content on Scorpiosec</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 15:40:59 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scorpiosec.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nothing to see here, yet.</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/projects/project1/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 15:40:59 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/projects/project1/</guid><description/></item><item><title>HTB: Trickster</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-trickster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:34 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-trickster/</guid><description>Platform: HackTheBox Link: Trickster Level: Medium OS: Linux Read this write up in french
Trickster is a multi-step machine beginning with the discovery of a subdomain containing a hidden .git directory, running an exploitable version of PrestaShop. Gaining initial access (with CVE-2024-34716) leads to the retrieval of database credentials from a configuration file, which help us find a user password.
System enumeration reveals an internal Docker interface with a host running a vulnerable instance of changedetection.</description></item><item><title>THM: Smol</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-smol/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 11:31:43 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/thm-smol/</guid><description>Platform: TryHackMe Link: Smol Level: Medium OS: Linux Read this write up in french
Smol focuses on exploiting vulnerabilities in WordPress plugins. The challenge begins with enumerating a WordPress site using WPScan, where we discover a plugin vulnerable to Local File Inclusion (LFI). This allows us to extract credentials and log into the WordPress dashboard. Within the dashboard, a private note directs us to the source code of the Hello Dolly plugin, which contains a backdoor.</description></item><item><title>HTB: MonitorsThree</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-monitorsthree/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 10:06:34 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-monitorsthree/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: MonitorsThree Level: Medium OS: Linux Read this write up in french
MonitorsThree begins with a website on port 80 and a Cacti instance hosted on a subdomain. The Forgot Password? feature on the main site is vulnerable to SQL injection, which we exploit to retrieve the admin user&amp;rsquo;s password. Using these credentials, we access the Cacti dashboard and leverage CVE-2024-25641 to gain an initial foothold on the system.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 17:31:29 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/about/</guid><description>Welcome to Scorpiosec, a place where a love of technology and a passion for self-directed learning come together. I&amp;rsquo;m an aspiring security professional and I have been studying cybersecurity since 2022. I decided to switch to the tech field after my Bachelor of Finance (I wasn&amp;rsquo;t feeling those spreadsheets). My goal is to get into red teaming or cloud security.
I created this blog because I wanted to showcase my skills and knowledge, it&amp;rsquo;s also a journal for my tech adventure.</description></item></channel></rss>