<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>HackTheBox on Scorpiosec</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/tags/hackthebox/</link><description>Recent content in HackTheBox on Scorpiosec</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 02:00:16 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scorpiosec.com/tags/hackthebox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HTB: Yummy</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-yummy/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2025 02:00:16 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-yummy/</guid><description>Platform: HackTheBox Link: Yummy Level: Hard OS: Linux Yummy presents a relatively small attack surface. A Local File Inclusion (LFI) vulnerability, allows access to the application&amp;rsquo;s source code. The review of the code reveals weak RSA key generation for JWT authentication, enabling the creation of higher-privilege tokens.
Further enumeration of the admin dashboard leads to the discovery of an SQL injection vulnerability in the search function. Combined with the FILE privilege, this allows us to write some content into files on the system, leading to remote code execution.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Cicada</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-cicada/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 17:24:03 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-cicada/</guid><description>Platform: HackTheBox Link: Cicada Level: Easy OS: Windows Cicada is an Active Directory domain controller. We are able to login through SMB using the guest account, allowing us to retrieve a note containing a password. By performing a RID brute force attack, we enumerate the domain users and discover valid credentials, which we use to authenticate via LDAP. Further enumeration reveals a password stored in a user’s description field, granting access to another SMB share containing a PowerShell script with hardcoded credentials.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Trickster</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-trickster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:34 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-trickster/</guid><description>Platform: HackTheBox Link: Trickster Level: Medium OS: Linux Trickster is a multi-step machine beginning with the discovery of a subdomain containing a hidden .git directory, running an exploitable version of PrestaShop. Gaining initial access (with CVE-2024-34716) leads to the retrieval of database credentials from a configuration file, which help us find a user password.
System enumeration reveals an internal Docker interface with a host running a vulnerable instance of changedetection.</description></item><item><title>HTB: MonitorsThree</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-monitorsthree/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 10:06:34 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-monitorsthree/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: MonitorsThree Level: Medium OS: Linux MonitorsThree begins with a website on port 80 and a Cacti instance hosted on a subdomain. The Forgot Password? feature on the main site is vulnerable to SQL injection, which we exploit to retrieve the admin user&amp;rsquo;s password. Using these credentials, we access the Cacti dashboard and leverage CVE-2024-25641 to gain an initial foothold on the system. Further exploration reveals additional password hashes, enabling us to pivot to another user via SSH.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Compiled</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-compiled/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 13:44:19 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-compiled/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Compiled Level: Medium OS: Windows Compiled begins with the discovery of a Gitea instance running on port 3000 and a compilation service on port 5000. By exploiting a vulnerability in the identified Git version (CVE-2024-32002), we gain initial access. We explore the system and uncover a database file containing user hashes and other critical information, allowing us to crack a password and perform a lateral movement.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Resource</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-resource/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 18:48:22 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-resource/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Resource Level: Hard OS: Linux Resource revolves around exploiting SSH and Certificate Authority files. The initial access is gained through a PHAR deserialization attack targeting a file upload feature. Next, we recover user credentials from a HAR file, which facilitates lateral movement to another user account. During this process, we discover certificate authority keys, enabling us to generate SSH keys and log in as yet another user.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Axlle</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-axlle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 17:00:51 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-axlle/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Axlle Level: Hard OS: Windows Axlle is a domain controller hosting a web server and an email server alongside standard Active Directory services. After conducting reconnaissance, we launch a phishing attack using a .xll attachment to gain an initial foothold. On the compromised target, we discover an .eml file containing details about an automated task. By leveraging this information, we craft a malicious .url file, enabling lateral movement to another user account and accessing the user flag.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Blazorized</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-blazorized/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 18:46:04 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-blazorized/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Blazorized Level: Hard OS: Windows Blazorized features a variety of Active Directory attacks. We begin by examining a web server hosting a Blazor WebAssembly application with restricted content access. Through enumeration, we locate several DLL files associated with the application. Decompiling one of these files reveals sensitive information, which we leverage to forge a JSON Web Token (JWT). This grants us access to an admin panel where we identify a SQL injection vulnerability, providing our initial foothold.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Editorial</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-editorial/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 21:00:55 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-editorial/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Editorial Level: Easy OS: Linux Editorial is an easy Linux machine with a few interesting challenges. The web application is vulnerable to Server-Side Request Forgery (SSRF), but it requires fuzzing internal ports to uncover sensitive data. By exploiting an API endpoint, we retrieve credentials that grant initial access to the system. During further enumeration, we discover a series of Git commits, one of which exposes credentials for another user, enabling lateral movement.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Blurry</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-blurry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 19:31:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-blurry/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Blurry Level: Medium OS: Linux The Blurry machine demonstrates how Python modules and specific Python features can be exploited to compromise systems. The challenge begins with access to a ClearML instance, containing various experiments tied to a project. Using CVE-2024-24590, we gain our initial foothold by uploading a malicious artifact through the API, allowing us to retrieve the user flag. This write-up will detail two distinct methods for privilege escalation, showcasing different approaches to fully compromise the system.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Freelancer</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-freelancer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 13:36:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-freelancer/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Freelancer Level: Hard OS: Windows Freelancer begins with a website that allows the creation of various types of accounts. After registering, we exploit an Insecure Direct Object Reference (IDOR) vulnerability to gain access to an admin account. On the admin page, we find a SQL terminal, which we leverage to obtain an initial foothold.
Further exploration of the system reveals passwords in a configuration file, which we run against a user list, enabling us to pivot to another account and obtain the user flag.</description></item><item><title>HTB: BoardLight</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-boardlight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 22:53:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-boardlight/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: BoardLight Level: Easy OS: Linux BoardLight begins with a subdomain discovery where we find a Dolibarr instance, which we access by using default credentials. The initial foothold is obtained via a PHP reverse shell coupled with an uppercase manipulation technique. From there we discover a configuration file containing credentials, allowing us to take over another account. Finally, we gain root privileges by exploiting a vulnerability in Enlightenment.</description></item><item><title>HTB: SolarLab</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-solarlab/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2024 13:33:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-solarlab/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: SolarLab Level: Medium OS: Windows SolarLab begins with a basic website that, after enumeration, offers no direct exploitation paths. Shifting focus to SMB, we discover a document in a file share containing credentials. These credentials grant access to ReportHub, accessible at a subdomain found during previous enumeration. Upon examining its functionality, we identify that it generates PDFs using the vulnerable ReportLab library (CVE-2023-33733), which allows us to exploit this and gain initial access, recovering the user flag.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Mailing</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-mailing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 23:42:37 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-mailing/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Mailing Level: Easy OS: Windows Mailing from HackTheBox is an interesting box. After our initial scan, we discover several email-related services. By exploiting an LFI vulnerability, we find two password hashes, and successfully cracking one of them gives us the admin password. We then use the recent MonikerLink vulnerability to retrieve a user&amp;rsquo;s NTLM hash, which provides us with our initial foothold. Privilege escalation is achieved by placing a malicious file in a specific directory where all files with the .</description></item><item><title>HTB: Runner</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-runner/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 19:24:15 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-runner/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Runner Level: Medium OS: Linux Runner starts with a basic website offering CI/CD solutions. Through subdomain enumeration, we uncover a vulnerable TeamCity instance (CVE-2023-42793), granting us access. A backup archive downloaded from this instance reveals a private SSH key and password hashes. Using the SSH key, we gain an initial foothold and retrieve the user flag. Further exploration uncovers another subdomain hosting a Portainer.io instance, which we access using the previously recovered credentials.</description></item><item><title>HTB: IClean</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-iclean/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 17:57:29 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-iclean/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: IClean Level: Medium OS: Linux IClean begins with a cleaning service website where we identify a form vulnerable to Cross-Site Scripting (XSS). Exploiting this vulnerability, we retrieve a session cookie and access the application dashboard. There, we discover an invoice generator susceptible to Server-Side Template Injection (SSTI), which provides our initial foothold. Further exploration reveals the database credentials, allowing us to recover password hashes. By cracking one of these hashes, we gain SSH access and retrieve the user flag.</description></item><item><title>HTB: WifineticTwo</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-wifinetictwo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 15:04:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-wifinetictwo/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: WifineticTwo Level: Medium OS: Linux WifineticTwo is a unique box focused on WiFi exploitation. The challenge begins with an accessible OpenPLC page using default credentials. Utilizing CVE-2021-31630, we gain an initial foothold and capture the user flag. Once inside the target system, we brute-force the WPS key, configure the wireless interface, and scan the default gateway to discover internal services. We then access the Lua Configuration Interface, set up a new password, log in via SSH, and retrieve the root flag.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Headless</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-headless/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 22:17:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-headless/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Headless Level: Easy OS: Linux Headless starts with a static website. Through enumeration, we identify a contact form vulnerable to Cross-Site Scripting (XSS), though basic payloads prove ineffective. By capturing the admin&amp;rsquo;s cookie value, we gain access to the dashboard page and establish our foothold through command injection. For privilege escalation, we exploit a custom script to take control of the root account.
Target IP address - 10.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Perfection</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-perfection/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jul 2024 14:05:10 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-perfection/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Perfection Level: Easy OS: Linux Perfection begins with a straightforward website. Through enumeration, we identify a vulnerability to Server-Side Template Injection (SSTI), which we exploit to gain an initial foothold. We then discover a database file containing password hashes, but our initial attempts to crack them are unsuccessful. After reading the user&amp;rsquo;s emails, we learn that the passwords follow a specific format. Using this information, we employ a mask attack with Hashcat and successfully recover the password.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Office</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-office/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 23:28:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-office/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Office Level: Hard OS: Windows The Office box is a Windows Server 2022 running as a domain controller. The website hosted on the web server uses an outdated version of Joomla, which is vulnerable to CVE-2023-23752. By exploiting this vulnerability, we leak the MySQL database password. After some enumeration, we find a valid username for the password, granting us access to a shared folder containing a pcap file.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Crafty</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-crafty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 21:19:39 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-crafty/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Crafty Level: Easy OS: Windows Crafty is a Windows Server 2019 running Minecraft 1.16.5, this version is vulnerable to Log4Shell (CVE-2021-44228) and after using a PoC of the exploit we gain our initial foothold. On the target system, we find an archive containing some credential that we use to obtain an administrative shell.
Target IP - 10.10.11.249
Scanning sudo nmap -sC -sV -p- -oA nmap/Crafty 10.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Pov</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-pov/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 12:42:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-pov/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Pov Level: Medium OS: Windows Pov starts with a basic static website. After some enumeration, we discover a subdomain leading to an ASP.NET website that turns out to be vulnerable to LFI. Leveraging this vulnerability, we are able to read a critical file exposing sensitive information that we use to exploit the ViewState mechanism of the website, granting us our initial foothold. After exploring the target system, we move laterally to another user after finding and revealing their credentials.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Bizness</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-bizness/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 21:18:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-bizness/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Bizness Level: Easy OS: Linux Bizness is showcasing a web application powered by Apache OFBiz. During our investigation of vulnerabilities in the software, we identify one that allows attackers to bypass authentication. Leveraging this exploit, we gain our initial foothold. Next, we stumble upon a directory for Apache Derby that containing numerous .dat files. Our task is to sift through these files. Using some command-line magic, we manage to retrieve a password hash.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Monitored</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-monitored/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 21:41:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-monitored/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Monitored Level: Medium OS: Linux Monitored emphasizes rigorous enumeration, the challenge starts with a login form for Nagios XI and directory enumeration leads to the discovery of more and more endpoints. After exhausting all the leads from our nmap TCP scan we make use of a UDP scan to find an exploitable service leading to the leakage of credentials that we use to login. We are able to discover the software version on the target and we leverage CVE-2023-40931 to add a new admin account to the Nagios XI instance to grant us access.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Surveillance</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-surveillance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 15:48:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-surveillance/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Surveillance Level: Medium OS: Linux Surveillance begins with the discovery of a web application running on port 80, after identifying the software version, we use CVE-2023-41892 to gain initial access. Through further exploration, we find a database backup leaking the user name and password hash for an admin user, which we utilize to SSH into the system and uncover an internal service. Leveraging SSH tunneling, we access the service and make use of CVE-2023-26035 to exploit it.</description></item></channel></rss>