<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>HackTheBox on Scorpiosec</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/tags/hackthebox/</link><description>Recent content in HackTheBox on Scorpiosec</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:34 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://scorpiosec.com/tags/hackthebox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>HTB: Trickster</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-trickster/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:34 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-trickster/</guid><description>Platform: HackTheBox Link: Trickster Level: Medium OS: Linux Read this write up in french
Trickster is a multi-step machine beginning with the discovery of a subdomain containing a hidden .git directory, running an exploitable version of PrestaShop. Gaining initial access (with CVE-2024-34716) leads to the retrieval of database credentials from a configuration file, which help us find a user password.
System enumeration reveals an internal Docker interface with a host running a vulnerable instance of changedetection.</description></item><item><title>HTB: MonitorsThree</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-monitorsthree/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 10:06:34 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-monitorsthree/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: MonitorsThree Level: Medium OS: Linux Read this write up in french
MonitorsThree begins with a website on port 80 and a Cacti instance hosted on a subdomain. The Forgot Password? feature on the main site is vulnerable to SQL injection, which we exploit to retrieve the admin user&amp;rsquo;s password. Using these credentials, we access the Cacti dashboard and leverage CVE-2024-25641 to gain an initial foothold on the system.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Compiled</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-compiled/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 13:44:19 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-compiled/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Compiled Level: Medium OS: Windows Read this write up in french
Compiled begins with the discovery of a Gitea instance running on port 3000 and a compilation service on port 5000. By exploiting a vulnerability in the identified Git version (CVE-2024-32002), we gain initial access. We explore the system and uncover a database file containing user hashes and other critical information, allowing us to crack a password and perform a lateral movement.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Axlle</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-axlle/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 17:00:51 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-axlle/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Axlle Level: Hard OS: Windows Read this write up in french
Axlle is a domain controller hosting a web server and an email server alongside standard Active Directory services. After conducting reconnaissance, we launch a phishing attack using a .xll attachment to gain an initial foothold. On the compromised target, we discover an .eml file containing details about an automated task. By leveraging this information, we craft a malicious .</description></item><item><title>HTB: Blazorized</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-blazorized/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 18:46:04 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-blazorized/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Blazorized Level: Hard OS: Windows Read this write up in french
Blazorized features a variety of Active Directory attacks. We begin by examining a web server hosting a Blazor WebAssembly application with restricted content access. Through enumeration, we locate several DLL files associated with the application. Decompiling one of these files reveals sensitive information, which we leverage to forge a JSON Web Token (JWT). This grants us access to an admin panel where we identify a SQL injection vulnerability, providing our initial foothold.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Editorial</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-editorial/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 21:00:55 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-editorial/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Editorial Level: Easy OS: Linux Read this write up in french
Editorial is an easy Linux machine with a few interesting challenges. The web application is vulnerable to Server-Side Request Forgery (SSRF), but it requires fuzzing internal ports to uncover sensitive data. By exploiting an API endpoint, we retrieve credentials that grant initial access to the system. During further enumeration, we discover a series of Git commits, one of which exposes credentials for another user, enabling lateral movement.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Blurry</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-blurry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 19:31:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-blurry/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Blurry Level: Medium OS: Linux Read this write up in french
The Blurry machine demonstrates how Python modules and specific Python features can be exploited to compromise systems. The challenge begins with access to a ClearML instance, containing various experiments tied to a project. Using CVE-2024-24590, we gain our initial foothold by uploading a malicious artifact through the API, allowing us to retrieve the user flag.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Freelancer</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-freelancer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 13:36:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-freelancer/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Freelancer Level: Hard OS: Windows Read this write up in french
Freelancer begins with a website that allows the creation of various types of accounts. After registering, we exploit an Insecure Direct Object Reference (IDOR) vulnerability to gain access to an admin account. On the admin page, we find a SQL terminal, which we leverage to obtain an initial foothold.
Further exploration of the system reveals passwords in a configuration file, which we run against a user list, enabling us to pivot to another account and obtain the user flag.</description></item><item><title>HTB: BoardLight</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-boardlight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 22:53:03 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-boardlight/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: BoardLight Level: Easy OS: Linux Read this write up in french
BoardLight begins with a subdomain discovery where we find a Dolibarr instance, which we access by using default credentials. The initial foothold is obtained via a PHP reverse shell coupled with an uppercase manipulation technique. From there we discover a configuration file containing credentials, allowing us to take over another account. Finally, we gain root privileges by exploiting a vulnerability in Enlightenment.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Headless</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-headless/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 22:17:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-headless/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Headless Level: Easy OS: Linux Read this write up in french
Headless starts with a static website. Through enumeration, we identify a contact form vulnerable to Cross-Site Scripting (XSS), though basic payloads prove ineffective. By capturing the admin&amp;rsquo;s cookie value, we gain access to the dashboard page and establish our foothold through command injection. For privilege escalation, we exploit a custom script to take control of the root account.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Crafty</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-crafty/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 21:19:39 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-crafty/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Crafty Level: Easy OS: Windows Read this write up in french
Crafty is a Windows Server 2019 running Minecraft 1.16.5, this version is vulnerable to Log4Shell (CVE-2021-44228) and after using a PoC of the exploit we gain our initial foothold. On the target system, we find an archive containing some credential that we use to obtain an administrative shell.
Target IP - 10.10.11.249
Scanning sudo nmap -sC -sV -p- -oA nmap/Crafty 10.</description></item><item><title>HTB: Bizness</title><link>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-bizness/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 21:18:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://scorpiosec.com/posts/htb-bizness/</guid><description>Platform: Hack The Box Link: Bizness Level: Easy OS: Linux Read this write up in french
Bizness is showcasing a web application powered by Apache OFBiz. During our investigation of vulnerabilities in the software, we identify one that allows attackers to bypass authentication. Leveraging this exploit, we gain our initial foothold. Next, we stumble upon a directory for Apache Derby that containing numerous .dat files. Our task is to sift through these files.</description></item></channel></rss>